Hi, this is Sean Hobson.
What we want you to understand is the most important thing about doing conditioning is being able to incorporate as many basketball skills into your conditioning as possible.
It does us no good to come out and run end to end just for conditioning purposes if we're not somehow trying to translate the skills of basketball into conditioning.
So what I like to do is try to take any basic skill that I can about the game of basketball, and somehow find a way to do conditioning.
If you're going to shoot the ball you might as well be shooting the ball constantly on the move, in a certain time frame, in order to get a good conditioning workout.
If you're going to dribble the ball or run the ball end to end, you might as well be dribbling while you're doing it.
If you can find a way to pass the ball while you're conditioning, that's good as well.
And try to build strength in to the basic skills of basketball is good as well.
So, when you're thinking about setting up conditioning for your practice, try to incorporate the basic skills of basketball into each conditioning drill that you do.
That way not only will your players be more well-rounded in the skills of basketball, they'll also get good conditioning at the same time.